Guide to the Center for the Study of Human Rights Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Training and Capacity Building Programs, 1987-2004.
  - Subseries III.3: The Religion, Human Rights and Religious Freedom Program, 1994-1999
    - Annual Conference
      - The Protection of Religious Minorities, Religious Freedom and Human Rights in Post Communist Europe, 1998 March 16-18, (5 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 1 to 5)
      - Islam and Human Rights in Post-Communist Europe, 1999 March 15-16, (6 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 6 to 11)
    - Other Conferences
      - Regulating Not-For-Profit Organizations in New Democracies, 1995 March 30-31 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Meeting of the Advisory Committee on Religious Freedom Abroad--Report from Paul Martin, 1997 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Conference on Religion in Russia (Title Unknown)--Notes, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - The Media and Religion: An Exploratory, Roundtable Examining Influences on the Coverage of Religion in the Media, 1998 December 2 (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Roundtable on the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 1999 April 16 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Courses
      - Syllabi and course listings, 1995-1996, (3 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 7 to 9)
      - Human Rights and Social Justice in Islamic History, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Religion Course--Papers on Proselytism, circa 1995 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Evaluations
      - Host Evaluation, 1995 (Box 20, Folder 12)
      - Evaluations by Fellows, 1995-1998, (3 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 13 to 15)
    - Grants
      - Rockefeller Foundation, 1999 (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Pew Charitable Trust--Notes, 1997 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Internships, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Orientation--Schedules, 1995 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, undated, (4 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 5 to 8)
    - Proposals, 1994-1995, (3 Folders) (Box 21, Folder 9 to 11)
    - Protest in Belgrade, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Reports
      - Annual Reports, 1994-1999, (3 Folders) (Box 22, Folder 2 to 4)
      - Monthly Email Reports, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Final Report to Pew Charitable Trusts, 1999 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Roundtables and Seminars
      - Brown Bag Series--Schedules, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Presentations by Fellows, 1997 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Schedules
      - Weekly Schedules, 1995 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Training Schedules, 1996 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Visits to Institutions, 1996-1997 (Box 22)
  - Subseries III.4: Other Training Programs, 1987-2003
    - CeSHRA--Review of Proposal, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Ecuador Project--Reports, 2000 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Global Rule of Law and Human Rights Program--Proposal, 1998 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Human Rights Connection--Coalition Building Materials, undated (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Human Rights Consortium (HRC) (Box 23)
    - Description and Goals, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Human Rights Colloquium--Reports, 2001, (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Human Rights University Network (SUR)--Workshop Materials, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - SUR Meeting Agenda, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - HRC Workplan, 2003 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Fundraising, 2004 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Human Rights and Democracy Education Program for Community Leaders in Uganda--Proposal, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Human Rights Education Programs (Box 23)
    - Primary Schools, 1997 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Secondary Schools, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Human Rights Distance Learning Project, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Indonesia Project--Reports, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - RIGHTS Consortium, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Rights Resources--Training Packets, 2002 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Rights Xchange, 2001-2002, (2 Folders) (Box 23, Folder 15 to 16)
    - Venezuela Project, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Conferences, Workshops, and Roundtables, 1995-2003.
  - 50/20 Human Rights Conference, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Advocacy and Citizen Participation, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Advocacy Institute, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Cameroon Pipeline Project Roundtable, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Colloquium on Capacity Building for Human Rights Organizations, 2001 May, (7 Folders) (Box 24, Folder 5 to 11)
  - International Human Rights Colloquium, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Sharing the Tools: Technologies for Human Rights (CUSHRID), 1998 May (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - University Seminar on Human Rights, 2001 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Using Data and Quantitative Analysis to Obtain Evidence for International Criminal Tribunals, 1997 April 12 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Wednesday Night Dinner Series, 1995-1996 (Box 25, Folder 5)